The memories. The madness. The music... The movie.
Pink Floyd: The Wall is a music, drama film directed by Alan Parker.
A troubled rock star descends into madness in the midst of his
physical and social isolation from everyone.
Pink, played by Bob Geldof.
Pink's Mother, played by Christine Hargreaves.
Pink's Father, played by James Laurenson.
Pink's Wife, played by Eleanor David.
Young Pink, played by Kevin McKeon.
Rock and Roll Manager, played by Bob Hoskins.
Pink Floyd – The Wall is a 1982 British live-action/animated musical surrealist drama film
directed by Alan Parker, based on Pink Floyd's 1979 studio album The Wall.
The screenplay was written by Pink Floyd vocalist and bassist Roger
Waters, with animation sequences directed by Gerald Scarfe.
The Boomtown Rats' lead vocalist Bob Geldof made his film debut as rock star Pink, who, driven to neurosis by the pressures
of stardom and traumatic events in his life, constructs an emotional and mental wall to protect himself.
However, this coping mechanism eventually
backfires, and Pink demands to be set free.
Like its associated album, the film is highly metaphorical, and
frequently uses both visual and auditory symbolism throughout.
It features little dialogue, instead being driven by
the music from the album throughout.
The songs used in the film have several differences from their album versions, and two of the songs
included, "When the Tigers Broke Free" and "What Shall We Do Now?", do not appear on the album.
Despite its turbulent production, the film received generally positive reviews, with praise for its
music and animation, and it has an established cult following among Pink Floyd fans.
The film explores themes of rock star, berlin wall,
paranoia, wall, descent into madness.
The tone is emotional.